Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records (PPFA II): SERIES III. Publications, 1930-80
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III. PUBLICATIONS
  - Conception Control, Local Methods, By Mary S. Calderone, M.D., reprint, Clinical Ob-Gyn 1964 (Box 92, Folder 89)
  - "Conception Control and the Medical Profession," By A.F. Guttmacher, M.D., Reprint, Human Fertility, March 1947 (Box 92, Folder 90)
  - "Conception Control by Plastic Cervix Cap," E. Grafenberg, M.D., R.L. Dickinson, M.D. 1944 (Box 92, Folder 91)
  - "Conception Control: A Public Health Responsibility," By Claude C. Pirece, M.D. 1941, 1942 (Box 92, Folder 92)
  - "Conception Control, A Clinical Evaluation of the Perceptin-Gel Method," 1956 (Box 92, Folder 93)
  - "Conception Control," R.L. Dickinson, M.D., Reprinted from Journal A.M.A., Dec. 1943 (Box 92, Folder 94)
  - "Condoms, A New Look," Reprint, Perspectives, Vol 4. No.4, Oct. 1972 (Box 92, Folder 95)
  - Congratulations, New Baby, undated (Box 92, Folder 96)
  - "Congressman's Report: A Time Bomb Called Population," By Morris K. Udall 1964 (Box 92, Folder 97)
  - Consumers Union Report on Family Planning, By A.F. Guttmacher, M.D. 1962-1966 (Box 92, Folder 98)
  - Contraception, Methods of, In the United States 1961 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - "Contraception: A Medical Problem of Growing Importance," by H.H. Jenkins M.D. 1940 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - "Contraception and Holiness, The Catholic Predicament," 1964 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Contraception and Planned Parenthood In a Private Practice, L. Dewees, M.D., G. Beebe, M.D., Out of Print 1940 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - "Contraceptive Clinics and Preventive Medicine," Dr. Alan F. Guttmacher 1942 (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - "Contraceptive Safe Period," S. Fleck, M.D., E.F. Snedeker, B.A., J. Rock, M.D. 1940 (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Contraceptive Services in the U.S., By Claude C. [Pierce], M.D., Out of Print 1943 (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - "Contraceptive Technology 1973-1974," The Emory University Family Planning Program, 1973 (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - "Contribution of P.P. to the Future of America," Frederick Osborn 1953 (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - "Control: By Man or Nature," Birth Control Review, January 1935 (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - "Control of Conception as a Public Health Responsibility," Read Before Miss. State Medical Society, Claude C. Pierce 1943 (Box 93, Folder 11)
  - Control of Conception, Present and Future, By R.L. Dickinson, M.D. 1929Out of Print, 1929 (Box 93, Folder 12)
  - "The Control of Fertility," Reprint, Jnl Amer. Med. Assn, Committee on Human Reproduction, Oct. 25, 1965 (Box 93, Folder 13)
  - "The Control of Fertility", By A. Stone, Scientific Amer. 1959, 1954 (Box 93, Folder 14)
  - Control of Human Reproduction, Research Program, undated (Box 93, Folder 15)
  - "Could the Supreme Court 'Abortion' Decisions be Lost?" 4/73 (Box 93, Folder 16)
  - "Counseling for Family Planning," By Miriam Manishoff, Reprint, Amer. Jnl of Nursing, Dec. 1966 (Box 93, Folder 17)
  - Crisis of Opportunity, A Capsule Case Study, 9/68 (Box 93, Folder 18)
  - "A Cure for Race Suicide," Reprinted from The Churchman 1930-1936 (Box 93, Folder 19)
  - "Current Status of Family Planning Programs in the United States," by G.W. Perkin, M.D. and David Rose, Oct. 1966 (Box 93, Folder 20)
  - "Daughters of DES Mothers," 7/77 (Box 93, Folder 21)
  - "Dealing with Reality, Birth Control and Pregnancy Counseling in a Student Health Center," E.K. Canfield, College Program, Reprint 1971 (Box 93, Folder 22)
  - "Discrimination Persists Against Pregnant Students Remaining in School," Reprint, Family Planning/Population Reporter, Youth and Student Affairs 1975 (Box 93, Folder 23)
  - "Dr. Guttmacher is the Evangelist of Birth Control," Reprint, New York Times 1969 (Box 93, Folder 24)
  - "Doctor Talks About Birth Control (A Teen-Age Fact Book)," by Alan F. Guttmacher, M.D., undated (Box 93, Folder 25)
  - "Do Teens Make Good Sex Counselors?" Reprint, Seventeen, Youth and Student Affairs 1975 (Box 93, Folder 26)
  - "Dear Doctor," Letters Pamphlet, 1944 Campaign, 1944 (Box 93, Folder 27)
  - "Demographic Dimensions of World Politics," By Dr. Philip Hauser, Reprint, Science, June 3, 1960 (Box 93, Folder 28)
  - "A Decade of Progress in Birth Control," Norman E. Hines 1940 (Box 93, Folder 29)
  - Robert L. Dickinson, Research Memorial, undated (Box 93, Folder 30)
  - "Directory of Family Planning Services in New York City," November 1965 (Box 93, Folder 31)
  - "Directory of Family Planning Services in New York City," 5/64 (Box 93, Folder 32)
  - Directory of Planned Parenthood Clinic Services 1938-1944 (Box 93, Folder 33)
  - "Directory of Clinic Services," Planned Parenthood 1950-1951 (Box 93, Folder 34)
  - "Do You Know How to Have Only Those Children You Wish?" undated (Box 93, Folder 35)
  - "Doctor's Marital Guide for Patients," Spanish Edition, Regular 1957 (Box 93, Folder 36)
  - The Doctor Talks With the Bride, Dr. Lena Levine 1939-1964 (Box 93, Folder 37)
  - "The Doctor Examines Marital Ills," Abraham Stone, M.D., Out of Print, undated (Box 93, Folder 38)
  - "The Doctor Talks About Menopause," Dodge, Eva F., M.D. 1945 (Box 93, Folder 39)
  - Does Overpopulation Mean Poverty? by Joseph Jones 1962 (Box 93, Folder 40)
  - "Do They Want Birth Control," By Margaret Sanger, Reprint from Woman's Digest, Nov. 1936 (Box 93, Folder 41)
  - Joy G. Dryfoos: Social and Economic Data About American Cities, February 1964 (Box 93, Folder 42)
  - "Dutch Methods of Birth Control," By Margaret Sanger, undated (Box 93, Folder 43)
  - Duty of Family Planning, Family Week 1949 (Box 93, Folder 44)
  - Doctor and Birth Control, Eastman, Nicholson, Guest Editorial, Va. Medical Monthly 1943 (Box 93, Folder 45)
  - "Do You Want A Baby Every Year?," 1962 (Box 93, Folder 46)
  - "Dynamics of the Marital Relationship," Stone, Levine, Reprint, Mental Health 1953 (Box 93, Folder 47)
  - "Eco-Catastrophe!" Dr. Paul Erlich, Ramparts, reprint, Sept. 1969 (Box 93, Folder 48)
  - "Economic Consequences of the Population Explosions," 1963 (Box 93, Folder 49)
  - "Economic Challenge of Population Growth," Annual Meeting, Nov. 10, 1964 (Box 93, Folder 50)
  - Education and Campaign Aids For 1963, Copeland, Gunther, Herter, Schmeck, 1962, A Mtg Talks & Keep Your Family Fit, 1962 (Box 93, Folder 51)
  - "Education for Marriage," By Abraham Stone, M.D., May 1956 (Box 93, Folder 52)
  - "Education for Marriage," Revisions 1961 (Box 93, Folder 53)
  - "Educational Needs of College Women for Marriage and Family Planning," Ed. C. Solomon 1963 (Box 93, Folder 54)
  - "84.9% Said 'Yes, But,'" Major Pamphlet 1944 (Box 93, Folder 55)
  - "El Don De La Vida," N.Y. State Dept. of Health, 1951, Received in C.R. Jan. 22, 1969, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 56)
  - Emotional Maladjustments, By Harvie Dej. Coghill, M.D. 1941 (Box 93, Folder 57)
  - "Employing the Married [Woman] Worker," circa 1944 (Box 93, Folder 58)
  - The Engagement Ring, "La Sortija de Compromiso," undated (Box 93, Folder 59)
  - "Escape from Fear," New Revised Edition 1962 (Box 93, Folder 60)
  - "Escape From Fear," ("Amor sin Miedo," Spanish Version), undated (Box 93, Folder 61)
  - "Establishing Contraceptive Services: University of Maryland," Jutta Hagner, Youth and Student Affairs, undated (Box 93, Folder 62)
  - "Ethics of Birth Control," By Algernon D. Black, Reprinted From the Standard, March 1936 (Box 93, Folder 63)
  - "Ethics of Family Planning," Statement by Clergymen's Nat'l Adv. Comm. 1960 (Box 93, Folder 64)
  - "Eugenics of Human Reproduction," By Frederick Osborn, Reprinted, Human Fertility from Feb. 1940 (Box 93, Folder 65)
  - Evaluation and Record Keeping for U.S. Family Planning Services, 11/68 (Box 93, Folder 66)
  - "Evaluation of the Barren Marriage," American Society for the Study of Sterility 1944 (Box 93, Folder 67)
  - "Evaluation of a New Contraceptive," By Aquiles J. Sobrero, M.D. 1960 (Box 93, Folder 68)
  - "Every Child a Wanted Child," 25 Years of the Birth Control Movement 1938 (Box 93, Folder 69)
  - "Every Woman Should Know More About Birth Control," New York Mirror, June 13, 1935 (Box 93, Folder 70)
  - Exhibits, Do It Yourself, undated (Box 93, Folder 71)
  - Exhibits, Medical 1965 (Box 93, Folder 73)
  - "Existence of an Optimum Interval Between Births," J. Yerushalmy 1945 (Box 93, Folder 74)
  - "Expecting Again," True Story 1956 (Box 93, Folder 75)
  - Exploding World Population 1955 (Box 93, Folder 76)
  - "Extramural Fertility Services," By A. Stone, M.D., F.E. Shields, M.D., Reprinted, Human Fertility, Sept. 1947 (Box 93, Folder 77)
  - Fact Book, Does OVERPOPULATION Mean POVERTY? 1962 (Box 93, Folder 78)
  - "Factors Influencing Offspring," By R.L. Day, M.D., Reprint, American Jnl Diseases of Children, A.M.A., Feb. 1967 (Box 93, Folder 79)
  - "The Factory Manager Learns the Facts of Life," Reprint, Harpers Magazine 1943 (Box 93, Folder 80)
  - "Facts About Planned Parenthood," Nov. 1968 (Box 93, Folder 81)
  - "Facts About Planned Parenthood World Population," 1968 (Box 93, Folder 82)
  - "Facts About the Threats to the Supreme Court Decisions on Abortion," 1973 (Box 93, Folder 83)
  - Facts and Figures on Legal Abortion of Importance to All Americans 1973 (Box 93, Folder 84)
  - Facts of Life for Children 1954 (Box 93, Folder 85)
  - "Facts: The Road to Survival," Campaign 1949 (Box 93, Folder 86)
  - "Facts and Figures," Planned Parenthood, Campaign 1949 (Box 93, Folder 87)
  - Facts and Figures, Planned Parenthood Campaign Worker's Handbook 1950-1952 (Box 93, Folder 88)
  - "Facts for Families," 1951 (Box 93, Folder 89)
  - Facts Speak for Planned Parenthood Fundraising 1953 (Box 93, Folder 90)
  - "Facts Without Argument," Bromley 1935 (Box 93, Folder 90)
  - "Fair Chance," Motion Pictures on P.P., undated (Box 93, Folder 91)
  - "A Fair Deal for Radio," By Mark Ethridge 1941 (Box 93, Folder 92)
  - "The Family in Psycho Therapy," Marynia F. Farnham, M.D., undated (Box 93, Folder 93)
  - "Family Limitation for the Rural Population," Dr. John Rodger 1940 (Box 93, Folder 94)
  - "Family Limitation," By Margaret Sanger, Out of Print, undated (Box 93, Folder 95)
  - "Family Limitations and the War," Henry Pratt Fairchild 1943 (Box 93, Folder 96)
  - "Family Planning," By Dr. Robert Hall, Reprint from My Baby, Nov. 1965 (Box 93, Folder 97)
  - "Family Planning: A Challenge to Health Workers of Every Nation," Dr. Clarence Gamble and Dr. Guttmacher 1966 (Box 93, Folder 98)
  - Family Planning: A Teaching Guide for Nurses, By Miriam Manisoff, R.N., February 1969 (Box 93, Folder 99)
  - "Family Planning and America's Future," By Samuel W. Anderson 1955 (Box 93, Folder 100)
  - "Family Planning and the Medical Assistance Program," By Fred Jaffe, Reprint from Med. Care, Jan.-Feb. 1968 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - "Family Planning and Poverty," Frederick S. Jaffe, Reprint, Journal of Marriage and the Family, Nov. 1964 (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - "Family Planning and Public Policy: Is the "Culture of Poverty" the New Cop-Out?," Jaffe, F.S. and Polgar, Reprint, Journal of Marriage and the Family 1968 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Family Planning and Rural Poverty: An Approach to Programming of Services 1968 (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - "Family Planning: A Blue Print for Action," National Conference on Family Planning, Washington, D.C., May 5-6, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - "Family Planning Democratized," Miriam Manisoff, Reprint, American Journal of Nursing, Oct. 1975 (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - "Family Planning Does Affect Your Business," Campaign 1952 (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - "Family Planning Education for the Patient," Miriam Manisoff 1968 (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Family Planning Educational Materials, University of North Carolina, Pop. Center, Chapel Hill, Feb. 1968 (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - "The Family Planning Field: Its Needs Are Far From Met," Foundation News, Sept.-Oct. 1974 (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - "Family Planning for the Poor," Reprint, New England Journal of Medicine, 10/13/66 (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - "Family Planning for Professionals," 1975 (Box 94, Folder 12)
  - "Family Planning Helps the Family," undated (Box 94, Folder 13)
  - "Family Planning in a Growing World," American Journal of Nursing 1964 (Box 94, Folder 14)
  - "Family Planning in an Exploding Population," by Rev. J.H. O'Brien, Ave Maria Reprint 1963 (Box 94, Folder 15)
  - "Family Planning, 'Its Role in Human Cost Accounting,'" by Dr. M.S. Calderone 1963 (Box 94, Folder 16)
  - Family Planning, A New Chapter, By Steven Polgar, Dr. A.F. Guttmacher, reprint, Columbia University Forum 1965 (Box 94, Folder 17)
  - Family Planning, New Chapter, By Elizabeth Ogg, Public Affairs Pamphlet 1964 (Box 94, Folder 18)
  - "Family Planning Services in a Mental Hospital," Eggert and Price, PPWP, Hospital and Commun. Psychiatry, Sept. 1969 (Box 94, Folder 19)
  - "Family Planning in Public Health Agencies," Reprint, Bulletin [of the] New York Academy of Medicine, January 1966 (Box 94, Folder 20)
  - "Family Planning, Medicaid, and the Private Physician," Publication No. 9, CFPPD 1970 (Box 94, Folder 21)
  - "The Family Planning Nurse Practitioner: Concepts and Results of Training," Manisoff, Davis, Kaminetsky, Payne; Reprint: Public Health Briefs, American Journal of Public Health 1976 (Box 94, Folder 22)
  - "Family Planning: One Aspect of Freedom to Choose," Nat'l Conference, Washington, D.C., Reprint 1966 (Box 94, Folder 23)
  - Family Planning: Policy Statement Prepared by Committee on Public Welfare Policy, APHA, Nov. 23, 1964 (Box 94, Folder 24)
  - "Family Planning Policy Statements: What Organizations say About Population Problems, and Birth Control," 1968 (Box 94, Folder 25)
  - Family Planning, Population Problems and the Secondary School Curriculum 1966 (Box 94, Folder 26)
  - "Family Planning Program for the Low-Income Family," By E.C. Corkey, Reprint, Journal of Marriage and Family, 11/64 (Box 94, Folder 27)
  - "Family Planning Programs in the United States," 1969 (Box 94, Folder 28)
  - "Family Planning, Public Policy and Intervention Strategy," By F.S. Jaffe, Journal of Social Issues 1966 (Box 94, Folder 29)
  - "Family Planning: A Radio Talk," Margaret Sanger, April 1935 (Box 94, Folder 30)
  - Family Planning: Senator Udall Offers Help, Reprint, New York Times, 6/20/65 (Box 94, Folder 31)
  - "Family Planning: A Special and Urgent Concern," By Martin Luther King, Reprint, Washington, D.C., May 1966 (Box 94, Folder 32)
  - "Financing Family Planning Services," by F.S. Jaffe, Reprint, American Journal of Public Health, June 1966 (Box 94, Folder 33)
  - Family Planning Service in Rural Puerto Rico, Jan. 1961 (Box 94, Folder 34)
  - Family Planning Training for Social Service, Edited by Miriam T. Manisoff 1970 (Box 94, Folder 35)
  - Family Planning Programs in the War Against Poverty (kit) 1966 (Box 94, Folder 36)
  - Family Planning Unit for your Hospital, Gordon W. Perkin, M.D., Reprint, Hospital Practice, 5/67 (Box 94, Folder 37)
  - "Family Planning, U.S.A.," 1973-1975 (Box 94, Folder 38)
  - Famine and Fertilizer, Dr. Raymond Ewell, State Univ. N.Y. Buffalo, Reprint, Chemical and Engineering News 1964 (Box 94, Folder 39)
  - "Family Planning within the Curriculum," By Sister Mary Helen, Reprint, Nursing Outlook 1967 (Box 94, Folder 40)
  - Dr. Richard L. Day's, "Fertility Control," 1966 (Box 94, Folder 41)
  - "Fertility Problems in India," Abraham Stone, Reprint, Fertility and Sterility 1953 (Box 94, Folder 42)
  - "Fewer Births, Better Living," By Dr. Stephen Enke, Sept. 1968 (Box 94, Folder 43)
  - FDA Report on the Oral Contraceptives by Adv. Committee on OB GYN, Food and Drug Administration 1966 (Box 94, Folder 44)
  - "Field Trial of a Contraceptive Foam in Puerto Rico," JAMA Reprint 1961 (Box 94, Folder 45)
  - Fiftieth (50th) Anniversary PP-WP, "Building Stronger Families, Happier Children," 1966 (Box 94, Folder 46)
  - "Fighting to Save the Earth from Man," Reprint, Time Magazine, Feb. 1970 (Box 94, Folder 47)
  - PP Film Guide, August 1962; 68-69-65-66-71-72 (Box 94, Folder 48)
  - Film News, undated (Box 94, Folder 49)
  - "The Fifth Freedom," Campaign Literature 1943 (Box 94, Folder 50)
  - "First Twenty Five Years," Margaret Sanger Research Bureau, undated (Box 94, Folder 51)
  - "Five Million Women," 1967 (Box 94, Folder 52)
  - "Florida Health Notes," Family Planning, Feb. 1966 (Box 94, Folder 53)
  - Foreign Aid Funds (for Birth Control), Reprints, July 1963 (1963) (Box 94, Folder 54)
  - "For Every Child," undated (Box 94, Folder 55)
  - "For Fewer Indians," Newsweek Reprint, Jan. 1952 (Box 94, Folder 56)
  - "For MEN Only, A Booklet About BIRTH CONTROL," 1966 (Box 94, Folder 57)
  - "For the Man Who Comes Back," 1945 Campaign Literature, 1945 (Box 94, Folder 58)
  - "For Legalized Birth Control," from New Republic 1934 (Box 94, Folder 59)
  - "Foresight from the Past," Juliet Barret Rublee, Reprint from 1916 Statement, 1952 (Box 94, Folder 60)
  - "For the Public Good," 1937 (Box 94, Folder 61)
  - Fortune Poll 1943, The American People, 1943 (Box 94, Folder 62)
  - Forum (Columbia University), "American Fertility Cult, Our Irresponsible Birth Rate," 1960 (Box 94, Folder 63)
  - "Four Years of Contraception as a Public Health Service in North Carolina," George M. Cooper 1941 (Box 94, Folder 64)
  - "Free Japan: A U.S. Headache," Reprint, U.S. News and World Report 1953 (Box 94, Folder 65)
  - "Frigidity," Dr. L. Levine and M. Gilman 1952 (Box 94, Folder 66)
  - "Fruits of Philosophy, [...] Dr. Knowlton Went to Jail," undated (Box 94, Folder 67)
  - How to Raise Money for PP Kit 1966 (Box 94, Folder 68)
  - "The Future is Now," 1970 (Box 94, Folder 69)
  - "[The] Future of Man's Environment," Reprint from Science Teacher, Jan. 1969 (Box 94, Folder 70)
  - "Gandhi and Mrs. Sanger Debate Birth Control," Reprint from Asia Magazine 1936 (Box 94, Folder 71)
  - "[The] Gift of Life," Published by Health Education Service 1951 (Box 94, Folder 72)
  - Gordon, Dr. John E., "Preventive Medicine and Epidemiology," Reprint, Am. Jnl. of Med. Sciences, 3/54 (Box 94, Folder 73)
  - "Group Premarital Counseling," Lena Levine, M.D. and Jeanne Brodsky, PSW 1949-1953 (Box 94, Folder 74)
  - "Group Therapy in Sexual Maladjustment," Dr. A. Stone and Dr. Lena L. Levine 1950 (Box 94, Folder 75)
  - "[The] Growth of World Population," from Nat'l Academy of Sciences Report, April 1963 (Box 94, Folder 76)
  - Growth of U.S. Population, Analysis, Nat'l Academy of Sciences, Nat'l. Research Council 1965 (Box 94, Folder 77)
  - Growth of World Population, Nat'l Academy of Sciences 1963 (Box 94, Folder 78)
  - "A Guide to Abortion Laws in the United States," Lawrence Lader, Redbook Reprint, June 1971 (Box 94, Folder 79)
  - "A Guidebook for Treasure Hunting," Fund Raising 1953 (Box 94, Folder 80)
  - "Guide to Public Affairs," Prepared by Public Policy Unit, CFPPD 1971 (Box 94, Folder 81)
  - "A Guide to Sexuality Handbooks," Prepared by Youth and Student Affairs PPFA 1974 (Box 94, Folder 82)
  - Guttmacher, Dr. Alan F., Babies by Choice or by Chance 1959-1961 (Box 94, Folder 83)
  - "Dr. Guttmacher is the Evangelist of Birth Control," by David Dempsey, Reprint, New York Times 1969 (Box 94, Folder 84)
  - Guttmacher, Dr. A.F.G., Cuban Report of Cuban Medical Conference, Reprint, Medical Tribune, Apr. 4, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 85)
  - Gynecology, Intra-Uterine Devices, Reprinted from Time 1964 (Box 94, Folder 86)
  - "Hacia Un Hogar Feliz," (Toward a Happy Home), Out of Print 1958 (Box 94, Folder 87)
  - Hall, Dr. Robert E., "Family Planning," Reprint from My Baby, Nov. 1965 (Box 94, Folder 88)
  - "Hank was Wanted Once," Fund Raising Pamphlet, undated (Box 94, Folder 89)
  - Harper's, Reprint, "What Women can do For Peace" by John Fisher, April 1963 (Box 94, Folder 90)
  - "Have Your Next Baby When You Want To," by Gordon E. Perkin, M.D., Assoc. Med. Dir., Formerly: "If you Don't Want a Baby," 1965 (Box 94, Folder 91)
  - "Health Benefits for Mother and Child," Dr. Abdel R. Omran, Reprint from World Health 1974 (Box 94, Folder 92)
  - Health Department Birth Control Program, Dr. Roy Norton 1939 (Box 94, Folder 93)
  - "Health Education for Responsible Parenthood: Preliminary Considerations," M.S. Calderone, M.D., Oct. 1964 (Box 94, Folder 94)
  - Health Examinations, A Manual for the General Practitioner, Medical Society County of New York, circa 1940 (Box 94, Folder 95)
  - "Heart Disease and Pregnancy," American Heart Association, undated (Box 94, Folder 96)
  - "Help Build Happy Families," Prepared for N.A.C.W. 1952 (Box 94, Folder 97)
  - "Here are the Facts," 1942 (Box 94, Folder 98)
  - "The Hidden Crisis," By John D. Rockefeller, 3rd, Reprint from Look Magazine, 2/9/65 (Box 94, Folder 99)
  - "Him and Her: The ABC's of Sex," 1969 (Box 94, Folder 100)
  - "Hints for Philanthropists," Campaign 1951 (Box 94, Folder 101)
  - "History of Contraception," Brooklyn Daily Eagle, Aug. 23, 1936 (Box 94, Folder 102)
  - "Holding Down the Population," Reprint, Newsweek, Inc., March 1970 (Box 94, Folder 103)
  - "Hospital Birth Control Services in U.S.," Reprinted from Human Fertility, Feb. 1941 (Box 94, Folder 104)
  - Hospitals, List: Family Planning, Prepared from American Hospital Assn. Guide, August 1, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 105)
  - "Hotlines: A New Ally to Family Planning," Gene Vadies, Marilyn Machlowitz, Youth and Student Affairs 1973 (Box 94, Folder 106)
  - "Hotlines and Sexuality: The Challenge of a Chronic Crisis," Jim McDonough, Center for Youth Development and Research, Youth and Student Affairs, undated (Box 94, Folder 107)
  - "The Houston Story: A Vasectomy Service in a Family Planning Clinic," Abel J. Leader, M.D., Reprint 1971 (Box 94, Folder 108)
  - "How Can We Have a Baby?" By Abraham Stone, M.D., Reprint, Redbook, May 1954 (Box 94, Folder 109)
  - "How Do I Talk: Family Planning," By Hannah D. Mitchell, Reprint, American Journal Pub. Health, May 1966 (Box 94, Folder 110)
  - "How I Answer My Patients' Questions about the Pill," by Sherwin A. Kaufman, Family Circle, June 1968 (Box 94, Folder 111)
  - "How Many Children Do You Want?," undated (Box 94, Folder 112)
  - "How Many Mothers Will You Save?," undated (Box 94, Folder 113)
  - "How Safe Are Intrauterine Contraceptives," Reprint, Medical World News, Dec. 3, 1965 (Box 94, Folder 114)
  - "How Safe is the Pill," by George Langmyhr, M.D., Reprint, Parents' Magazine, October 1967 (Box 94, Folder 115)
  - "How to Establish a Planned Parenthood Center," Dr. Abraham Stone 1952 (Box 94, Folder 116)
  - "How to Organize a Local Planned Parenthood Group, A Guide for New Affiliates," 1968 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - "The How-To Handbook on Organizing a Student Sex Information Project," Reprint, Youth and Student Affairs 1974 (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - "How to Prevent Organizational Dry Rot," Reprint from Harper's Magazine, 10/65 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - "How to Raise Money for Planned Parenthood," undated (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - "How to Talk to Your Teenagers About Something That's Not Easy to Talk About," undated (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - "How to Tell Your Child About Sex," Public Affairs Pamphlet 1953 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Human Biology, A Record of Research, By G.W. Beebe and Murray A. Geisler, Reprint, Human Biology 1942 (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Human Biology, "On the Interval Between Successive Birth and Its Effect on Survival of Infant," By J. Yerushalmy 1945 (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Literature: The Humanist, American Humanist Association 1953 (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - "The Human Race Has, Maybe, Thirty Five Years Left," By David Lyle, Reprint, Esquire Magazine 1967 (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - Planned Parenthood World Population Handbook 1963 (Box 95, Folder 11)
  - "IPPF, Programme for a World Problem," Reprint, March 1964 (Box 95, Folder 12)
  - "I Believe in Birth Control," Hepburn, Ethel R., undated (Box 95, Folder 13)
  - "Iberoamérica y el control de la Natilidad," por Albert Maisel, Reprint, Spanish Reader's Digest 1964 (Box 95, Folder 14)